DARWIN ANDERSON Software Engineer Full-Stack Developer

Personal Information

ADDRESS

1021 Grandeview Blvd. Apt 216

Huntsville, AL. 35824

PHONE

256-275-1628

☑ EMAIL

darwin.p.anderson@gmail.com

in LinkedIn

darwin-anderson-38a583173

G GITHUB

github.com/darwinpanderson

₩ GITLAB

gitlab.com/DarwinAnderson

PROFICIENCIES

Language Proficiencies

- HTML 5 / CSS / SASS
- PHP (Procedural & OOP)
- Ruby on Rails
- MySQL / PostgreSQL
- Javascript / AngularJS
- Node.JS
- AJAX
- SOAP/REST
- Linux Server & System
- Python / Django
- Golang

Skill Proficiencies

- Solution Analysis
- UI/UX Design
- API design
- Full-Stack Deployment
- Database Administration
- GIT Repository
 - Management
- Project Planning and Management
- Docker Containerization
- CI/CD Deployment

I am a Software Developer with five years of experience specializing in web application development, data ETL processes, DevOps, server administration, database architecture, continuous integration and delivery(CI/CD), and zero-downtime deployments. I have developed and implemented API modules, accounting systems, integrated payment processing modules, database schemas, analytics tools, social media integrations, and system redesigns for both small and large scale projects. My greatest strengths are my analytical and organizational skills, which enable me to properly plan projects with AGILE methodologies and convey concepts across all levels of experience and technical acumen.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Imagehawk, Inc. - Huntsville, AL Developed merge process and operations processes for codebase updates Primary developer for project merging deviated development branches back to single master 2019 - CURRENT Primary developer for multi-disciplinary clinic management product Met with clients alongside CEO and COO as technical advisor Assessed and evaluated data architecture and developed new data schemas for future implementation Software Engineer Partcycle Technologies - Florence, AL Developed ETL tools and processes that evaluated over one million inventory items nightly Developed numerous features for online marketplace servicing both consumer and commercial customers 2018 - 2019 Utilized CI/CD techniques to deploy update patches hourly Leveraged AWS and Heroku resources to develop DevOps processes and reporting tools Attended conferences and functions alongside CEO and COO as technical advisor SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER IMS Enterprises, Inc. - Florence, AL Developed tools for internal administration and customer support usage Implemented updates to legacy systems to bring them 2013 - 2018 up to security and W3C standards Lead developer for several account management and registration systems Primary DevOps engineer for numerous client server

EDUCATION

NORTHWEST SHOALS COMMUNITY COLLEGE

Associates of Applied Science - Computer
Science

Project Manager for 47inf.org site redesign

environments